Salvador Luria Papers 1923-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works by Luria, 1938-1997; 2.75 linear feet
  Luria's typewritten and handwritten outlines, preparatory notes, research, and drafts for articles, books, and lectures. This series is arranged alphabetically by title, and cross-references are given for photographs which appear in this series. Some of the works are co-authored with colleagues and students. For each work, the notes and drafts are filed together. This series includes reviews of others' books; notes and drafts for the books, General Virology and Life: The Unfinished Experiment; and notes and drafts for lectures, including the Nobel lecture, "Phage, Colicins, and Macroregulatory Phenomena." The earliest item in this series is "Le Dosi Profonde e le Curve di Isodose Nella Terapia Roentgen ad Altissima Tensione," a paper that Luria wrote in Italian at the University of Rome. Also in this series is a bibliography of Luria's works until 1983. Also included are letters to the editors of the Boston Globe and the New York Times that were published. These letters are filed under the published title. Unpublished letters to the editor are filed in Series I (Correspondence) under the name of the newspaper.
  - Abstract, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Alioshia as Well as Ivan Sakharov Speaks, 15 Sep. 1974 (Box 42)
  - Alternative Tasks for Biologists--Lecture, 1 Nov. 1973 (Box 42)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science--Lecture, Feb. 1976 (Box 42)
  - An Analysis of Bacteriophage Multiplication, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Analysis of DNA, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Babi Yar, Warsaw and Vietnam, 14 Mar. 1968 (Box 42)
  - Bacterial Physiology and Neurophysiology--Seminar at Stanford University, 15 Apr. 1983 (Box 42)
  - The Bacterial Protoplasm, [1959] (Box 42)
  - A Bacterial System for Secretion of Proteins--Invention with Joan L. Suit, [198-] (Box 42)
    -See also Ser.III, A System for Release of
  - Les Bactéries Lysogènes et la Notion de Provirus by François Jacob--Review, 1957 (Box 42)
  - Beliefs, 1987 (Box 42)
  - Belmont, Massachusetts--Lecture, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Bibliography, 1969, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Biological Aspects of Ethical Principles, [1976] (Box 42)
  - Biology by Helena Curtis--Review, [1968] (Box 42)
  - Biology and Social Responsibility, [1968] (Box 42)
  - [Biology of the Human Complexity of Language, Culture, and Values]--Book Notes, 1988 (Box 42)
  - Changes in Enzymes Following Virus Infection and Possible Bearing on Mechanisms of Tumorigenesis and Its Control (Box 42)
  - Chemically Induced Modification of Viral Nucleic Acids (Box 42)
  - A Christmas Parable in One Act, 25 Dec. 1973 (Box 42)
  - [Col Plasmids], [1980] (Box 42)
  - Colicin-Tolerant Mutants: An Approach to the Genetics of Membranes, [1967] (Box 42)
  - Colicin-Tolerant Mutants of E. Coli -- with Rosa Nagel de Zwaig, 1967 (Box 42)
  - Colicins (Box 42)
    - Folder #1, [1971] (Box 42)
    - Folder #2, [1971] (Box 42)
  - Colicins and Col Plasmids -- with Joan L. Suit, 1985 (Box 42)
  - Colicins K and E1 Increase the Permeability of Membranes for Ions and Organic Molecules in Liposomes and Bacteria--with Celik Kayalar (Box 42)
  - Collaborative Research, Inc.--Notes, [1967] (Box 42)
  - Conformity vs. Concern, Apr. 1976 (Box 42)
  - Control Functions of Bacteriophages and Bacteriocins (Box 42)
  - Control of Bacterial Properties by Bacteriophage Genes, n.d. (Box 42)
  - [Correspondence Among Scientists] -- Fiction, [1981] (Box 42)
  - Crimes and Science Fellowships, 1961 (Box 42)
  - [Denver--Lecture], n.d. (Box 43)
  - The Dilemma of Cancer--Lecture, 16 Jul. 1978 (Box 43)
  - Directed Genetic Change: Perspectives from Molecular Genetics, n.d. (Box 43)
  - DNA and Emergence (Box 43)
  - DNA and Glucosylation in T-Even Phage: Genetic Determination and Role in Phage-Host Interaction--with Helen R. Revel, 1969 (Box 43)
  - [Domestic Cooperation], n.d. (Box 43)
  - Le Dosi Profonde e le Curve di Isodose Nella Terapia Roentgen ad Altissima Tensione, 1938 (Box 43)
    in Italian
  - Downing of Flight 655 Was an Act of Terrorism, 17 Jul. 1988 (Box 43)
  - Drug Bill Assailed, 26 Apr. 1970 (Box 43)
  - Effects of Colicin K on a Mutant of Escherichia Coli Deficient in Ca2+, Mg2+-Activated ATPase--with Charles A. Plate, Joan L. Suit, and Anton M. Jetten, 1974 (Box 43)
  - Effects of Diet on Conversion of Aflatoxin B1 to Bacterial Mutagen(s) by Rats in Vivo and by Rat Hepatic Microsomes in Vivo--with Joan L. Suit, Adrianne E. Rogers, and M.E.R. Jetten (Box 43)
  - Energy Requirement for the Initiation of Colicin Action in Escherichia Coli--with Anton M. Jetten and M.E.R. Jetten (Box 43)
  - Enzyme Sythesis Directed by Nonglucosylated T-Even Bacteriophages in Restrictive Hosts--with Stanley M. Hattman and Helen R. Revel (Box 43)
  - Epigraph: From Josephus, Sudean Wars, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Ethical and Institutional Aspects of Recombinant DNA Technology, 1982 (Box 43)
  - Ethical Aspects of the New Perspectives in Biomedical Research, [1971] (Box 43)
  - Expression of the Cloned ColEl kil Gene in Normal and Kilr E. Coli--with Mario Altieri, Joan L. Suit, and M.-L. J. Fan (Box 43)
  - Expression of the kil Gene of the ColEl Plasmid Causes Release of Periplasmic Enzymes of Colicin Without Cell Death in Kilr Mutants--with Joan L. Suit, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Far from the Madding Crowd--Lecture at Massachusetts General Hospital, 5 Dec. 1980 (Box 43)
  - A Farewell, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Feminism--Book Notes, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Few Raised Voices, 1986 (Box 43)
  - From Gene to Oncogene, 14 Aug. 1986 (Box 43)
  - From Phage to Cancer, [1977] (Box 43)
  - Full Circle, 18 Sep. 1974 (Box 43)
  - General Virology (Box 43)
    - Folders #1-3, 1967 (Box 43)
    - Folders #4-5, 1967 (Box 44)
  - General Virology, 1987 (Box 44)
  - Genesis, [197-] (Box 44)
  - Genetics and Physiological Studies on Colicin-Tolerant Mutants--with Rosa Nagel de Zwaig (Box 44)
  - The Goals of Science, 1976 (Box 44)
  - Government by Intimidation, 1 Nov. 1972 (Box 44)
  - Growing up Sensible--Convocation Address at Brown University Commencement, 1975 (Box 44)
  - A Heat-Sensitive Beta-D-Galactosidase from Shigella Dysenteriae--Abstract with S. Sarkar, 1962 (Box 44)
  - Humanistic Courses: Does Dean Count?, n.d. (Box 44)
  - Initiation of Transcription is Temperature-Dependent in an E. Coli Mutant with ts Adenylate Kinase--with Joan L. Suit and Charles A. Plate, [1975] (Box 44)
  - An Insult, 31 Oct. (Box 44)
  - Integrity in Research (Box 44)
    -See Ser.III, What Makes a Scientist
  - Interaction of Colicins with Membranes--Report, 26 Jun. 1987 (Box 44)
  - Isolation of a Suppressor Mutant Strain of B. Subtilis 168--with Constantine P. Georgopoulos, 1968 (Box 44)
  - Jacques Monod, Scientist, Humanist, and Friend, 1978 (Box 44)
  - Jesup Lectures, n.d. (Box 44)
  - The Kingdom of Ideas, n.d. (Box 44)
  - A Latter-Day Rationalist's Lament, [1970] (Box 44)
  - Lethal Action of Endogenous Colicin E1--with Joan L. Suit and Mei-Ling Fan (Box 44)
  - Life on Earth, [1976] (Box 44)
  - Life: The Unfinished Experiment (Box 44)
    - Folders #1-2, [197-] (Box 44)
    - Folders #3-6, [197-] (Box 45)
  - Looking at the Humanities from the Outside--Lecture, 28 Oct. 1972 (Box 45)
  - Macromolecular Syntheses in an adk Mutant of Escherichia Coli--with Joan L. Suit and Mei-Ling J. Fan, [1980] (Box 45)
  - Man Has Broken Nature's Code--Now What?, 30 Dec. 1967 (Box 45)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology--Lecture, Dec. 1982 (Box 45)
  - The Meaning of Sanctuary, n.d. (Box 45)
  - A Method for Counting the Number of Copies of an F1 Factor--with Patricia French, n.d. (Box 45)
  - The Microbiologist and His Times--Lecture, 7-May-68 (Box 45)
  - The Mistaken Identity of Colicin A, [1981] (Box 45)
  - Modern Biology: A Terrifying Power, 20 Oct. 1969 (Box 45)
  - Molecular Biology: Past, Present, and Future--Lecture, 1970 (Box 45)
  - Molecular Biology: Past, Present, Future--Lecture, 26 Aug. 1970 (Box 45)
  - Molecular Structure and the Functional Organization of Cellular Constituents, 1965 (Box 45)
  - Moral, Material Disaster, 20 Oct. 1967 (Box 45)
  - National Symposium on Genetics and the Law--Lecture, 20-May-75 (Box 45)
  - A New Class of Temperature-Dependent Colicin-Tolerant Mutants--with Rosa Nagel de Zwaig (Box 45)
  - No Excuse, 24 Jan. (Box 45)
  - On Research Styles and Allied Matters, 1972 (Box 45)
  - On Teaching Biology in a Biological Revolution, Mar. 1969 (Box 45)
  - On the Evolution of the Lactose-Utilization Gene System in Enteric Bacteria, n.d. (Box 45)
  - On Viewing American Indian Art Exhibit, 28 Feb. 1972 (Box 45)
  - Paris--Lecture, n.d. (Box 46)
  - Paris. Lisbon. New York--Novel, [1981] (Box 46)
    See also Ser.I, The New Yorker
  - The Pentagon and MIT (Box 46)
  - Permeability to Ions and Organic Molecules Induced by Colicin K on Liposomes--with Celik Kayalar (Box 46)
  - Perspectives on Transport in Bacteria, n.d. (Box 46)
  - Phage, Colicins, and Macroregulatory Phenomena--Nobel Lecture, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Pisa--Lecture, 1977 (Box 46)
  - A Professor Takes Exception, Jun. 1962 (Box 46)
  - Proposal on Nomenclatures--with Alfred D. Hershey, Max Delbrück, and August H. Doermann, 14 Mar. 1946 (Box 46)
  - Quantum Mechanics--Book notes, n.d. (Box 46)
  - The Recognition of DNA in Bacteria, [1970] (Box 46)
  - Reflections on Democracy, Science, and Cancer--Lecture at American Academy of Arts and Sciences, [1976] (Box 46)
  - A Reminiscence on the Department of Genetics, Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Harbor, n.d. (Box 46)
  - The Role of the University: Ivory Tower, Service Station, or Frontier Post?--with Zella Luria, 1970 (Box 46)
  - Science, Technology, and Responsibility--Lecture before the Ford Hall Forum, [1970] (Box 46)
    See also card catalog for manuscript
  - Science, Technology, and Responsibility--Lecture before Asociacion Venezolana para el Avance de la Ciencia, [1971] (Box 46)
    See also Ser.I, Asociacion Venezolana
  - Scuola Normale Superiore--Lectures, 1977 (Box 46)
  - Separation of Transport and Accumulation of Beta-Galactosides by Colicins--with Kay L. Fields and Ron H. Ruby, 1966 (Box 46)
  - The Single Artificer--Lecture, 31 Mar. 1986 (Box 46)
    See also Ser.I, Gustavus Adolphus College
  - Slippery When Wet: Being an Essay on Science, Technology, and Responsibility--Lecture at American Philosophical Society, 20 Apr. 1972 (Box 46)
  - The Soluble and the Insoluble--with Zella Luria, 1974 (Box 46)
    See also Ser.I, The Cooper Union for The
  - Stages in Colicin K Action, as Revealed by the Action of Trypsin--with Charles A. Plate, 1972 (Box 47)
  - [Structure of Molecular Biology], [1988] (Box 47)
  - A System for Release of Certain Proteins from Escherichia Coli Cells, 1986 (Box 47)
    -See also Ser.III, A Bacterial System for
  - Teller's Road to Disaster--with B.T. Feld, G. Holton, M. Meselson, W.F. Schreiber, P. Morrison, J. Orear, and E. Salpeter (Box 47)
  - A Test for Penicillin Sensitivity of Staphylococcus, 31 Jul. 1945 (Box 47)
  - Themes Beyond Chemistry. [Review of] The Periodic Tables by Primo Levi, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Thoughts on Art, Science, and Politics--Lecture, 17 Feb. 1987 (Box 47)
  - Transduction of Lactose-Utilizing Ability among Strains of E. Coli and S. Dysenteriae and the Properties of the Transducing Phage Particles--with J.N. Adams and R.C. Ting, 1960 (Box 47)
  - Transduction of the rec+ Gene to Escherichia Coli rec- Mutants--with Israel Hertman, n.d. (Box 47)
  - Transferable Drug Resistance Factor R by S. Mitsuhashi--Preface, Sep. 1976 (Box 47)
  - Transmembrane Channels Produced by Colicin Molecules--with Joan L. Suit, 1980 (Box 47)
  - Treat Laureate Fairly, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Two Cultures Are Better Than One (Box 47)
    -See Ser.III, The Soluble and the
  - [Unidentified], n.d. (Box 47)
  - University of Washington--Lecture, [197-] (Box 47)
  - Value of Space Study, 26 Sep. 1969 (Box 47)
  - Vietnam: A National Catastrophe--with Albert Szent-Györgyi, 1967 (Box 47)
  - A View of Life--with Stephen J. Gould and Sam Singer, [1979-1980] (Box 47)
  - Viruses: Structure, Reproduction and Origin--Lecture, 1951 (Box 47)
    See also Ser.I, University of Michigan
  - What Can Biologists Solve?, 7 Feb. 1974 (Box 47)
  - What Does Microbiology Contribute to the Teaching of Biology?, [1968] (Box 47)
  - What Makes a Scientist Cheat, May-75 (Box 47)
  - What the Cell Knows and How It Can Learn, 1966 (Box 47)
- Series IV. Works by others, 1944-1990; 11 linear feet
  articles, notes, reports, and papers written by colleagues and students of Luria. This series is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title. The series attests to Luria's practice of keeping up-to-date with the work of others in his field. Many authors are represented by four or more manuscripts, including Max Delbrück, Renato Dulbecco, François Jacob, Eduard Kellenberger, Ole Maalfe, Aaron Novick, Gunther S. Stent, and George Streisinger. Also included is a copy of James D. Watson's Ph.D. thesis (Luria was one of Watson's advisors) and a copy of a paper that Francis H.C. Crick wrote for the RNA Tie Club. Any works that Luria co-wrote with students and colleagues are filed in Series III alphabetically by title. Cross references are given for photographs which appear in this series.
  - The Genetic Properties of the Transducing Particles of Bacteriophage P1, 1959; Adams, Mary Jane Neal (Box 48)
  - Segregation Data, Dec. 1959; Adams, Mary Jane Neal (Box 48)
  - Segregation Following Superinfection, n.d.; Adams, Mary Jane Neal (Box 48)
  - Segregation Patterns, n.d.; Adams, Mary Jane Neal (Box 48)
  - The Glucose Effect and the Galactose Enzymes of Escherichia Coli: Correlation Between Glucose Inhibition of Induction and Inducer Transport, Adhya, Sankar and H. Echols (Box 49)
  - The Amount of Galactose Genetic Material in ldg Bacteriophages with Different Densities, n.d.; Adler, Julius and Bonnie Templeton; Adler, Julius; Templeton, Bonnie (Box 49)
  - Interazione TRA DNE e RNA di B. Stearothermophilus Interessante Solo la Metà del DNA Totale, 15 Dec. 1964; Ageno, M., M. Arca, E. Dore, et al.; Ageno, Mario; Arca, M.; Dore, E. (Box 49)
  - Biochemical and Morphological Aspects of LSD Pharmacology, 1967; Aghajanian, George K.; Freedman, Daniel X. (Box 49)
  - Polyoma Regulatory Region as Probe for Mouse Cell Differentiation, n.d.; Amati, Paolo (Box 49)
  - Segregation of New Lysogenic Types During Growth of a Doubly Lysogenic Strain of E. Coli K12, 1954; Appleyard, R.K. (Box 49)
  - Segregation of Lambda Lysogenicity During Bacterial Recombination in E. Coli K12, n.d.; Appleyard, R.K. (Box 49)
  - The Mechanism of Protein Synthesis, 1967; Attardi, Giuseppe (Box 49)
  - A Membrane-Associated RNA of Cytoplasmic Origin in HeLa Cells, n.d.; Attardi, Giuseppe (Box 49)
  - The Pedigrees of Some Mutant Strains of Escherichia Coli K12, [1972]; Bachmann, Barbara J. (Box 49)
  - The Replication of Picornaviruses, [196-]; Baltimore, David (Box 49)
  - Replication of RNA Viruses. IV. Initiation of RNA Synthesis by the QBeta RNA Polymerase, n.d.; August, J.T.; Banerjee, A.K.; Eoyang, Lillian; Hori, K. (Box 49)
  - Mutations Affecting the Inhibition of Eberthella Typhosa by Certain Carbohydrates, Jan. 1948; Barkulis, Ingebjorg Lid (Box 49)
  - Difficulties for the Irreversibility Hypothesis in the Breakage-Rejoining Models for T4-DNA Replication, n.d.; Barricelli, Nils Aall (Box 49)
  - Effects of Bacteriophage fd Infection on the E. Coli HB11 Envelope: Morphological and Biochemical Study, 1985; Bayer, Manfred E.; Bayer, Margret (Box 49)
  - Incorporation of Diaminopimelic Acid into Escherichia Coli Membranes, n.d.; Bayer, Manfred E.; Bayer, Margret (Box 49)
  - Replications of a Bacterial Plasmid and an Episome in Escherichia Coli, 1970; Bazaral, Michael; Helsinki, Donald R. (Box 49)
  - Drugs that Turn on the Law--Lecture, 8 Nov. 1969; Bazelon, David L. (Box 49)
  - Medical Progress and the Legal Process--Lecture, 22 Jan. 1969; Bazelon, David L. (Box 49)
  - Virus of Avian Myeloblastosis. XVI. Kinetics of Cell Growth and Liberation of Virus in Cultures of the Myeloblasts, Mar. 1960; Beaudreau, G.S.; Becker, C.; Stim, T. (Box 49)
  - Restoration of Operon Activity by Suppressors, n.d.; Beckwith, Jonathan R. (Box 49)
  - Aspects of Sign Language and Its Structure, Bellugi, Ursula; Klima, Edward S. (Box 49)
  - [Lectures], n.d.; Benedek, G. (Box 50)
  - Chloramphenicol and Puromycin as Inducers of Colicinogenic Bacteria, 1970; Ben-Gurion, Renana (Box 50)
  - Induced Synthesis of Enzymes in Bacteria Analyzed at the Cellular Level, Benzer, Seymour (Box 50)
  - Chromosome Replication in Escherichia. I. Lack of Influence of the Integrated F Factor, n.d.; Berg, Claire M.; Caro, Lucien G. (Box 50)
  - Replication and Genetic Exchange in the Genome of Escherichia Coli K-12, 1966; Berg, Claire M. (Box 50)
  - The Detection and Study of Tumor Viruses with the Electron Microscope: Present Facts and Problems as Seen by a Morphologist, Bernhard, W. (Box 50)
  - Multiplicity Reactivation of Ultraviolet-Irradiated VI-Phage II of Salmonella Typhi, [1956]; Bernstein, Aleck (Box 50)
  - Health as the Physician Views It and the Use of Space Technology to Achieve and Maintain It, 2 Sep. 1971; Berry, Charles A. (Box 50)
  - "The Effect of Chocomphenicol, p-fl Phenyl Alanine and 50H Uridene + DL Ethionine on the Curving Effect as Tested in Synthetic Medium", Boezi, John; Kyndberg, Robert (Box 50)
  - Integration of Genetic Characters Transferred in Matings Between Escherichia Coli and Shigella Dysenteriae, 1958; Boice, Lu Belle (Box 51)
  - Summary of Plvir Experiments, n.d.; Boice, Lu Belle (Box 51)
  - Test for Lysogeny in Cells of E. Coli and Sh. Dysenteriae from Transduced Colonies, Boice, Lu Belle and S. Sarkar (Box 51)
  - Transfer of Transducing Prophages in Bacterial Matings, 1962; Boice, Lu Belle (Box 51)
  - Bacterial Flagella, 5 Jan. 1965; Botstein, David (Box 51)
  - Defense Against Unwanted Change--Lecture, n.d.; Boulding, Kenneth E. (Box 51)
  - [Lecture Notes for 8.204J], 1978; Brecher (Box 51)
  - Replication and Recombination in Bacteriophage. A Review of Pertinent Data and a Molecular Interpretation of the Partial Replica Hypothesis, Bresch, Carsten, 1921- (Box 51)
  - Zum Paarungsmechanismus von Bacteriophagen--Translated by Salvador E. Luria, 1955; Bresch, Carsten, 1921- (Box 51)
  - The Calcium-Proton Antiport of Escherichia Coli, n.d.; Brey, Robert N.; Rosen, Barry P. (Box 51)
  - Energy Transduction in Escherichia Coli: A New Mutation Affecting the Fo Portion of the ATP Synthetase Complex, n.d.; Brey, Robert N.; Hasan, Syed M.; Rosen, Barry P. (Box 51)
  - Fragmentation of Colicins A and E1 by Cell Surface Proteases, Brey, Robert N. (Box 51)
  - Fragmentation of Colicins by Cells and Membranes, 1981; Brey, Robert N. (Box 51)
  - Some Possible Effects of a Large Scale American Shelter Program on the Soviet Union and Other Nations, Bronfenbrenner, Urie (Box 51)
  - [Unidentified], [1966]; Bronk, Detlev W., (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975 (Box 51)
  - The Biosynthesis of Folic Acid. VIII. Purification and Properties of the Enzyme That Catalyzes the Production of Formate from Carbon 8 of GTP, Brown, Gene M.; Burg, Alan W. (Box 51)
  - The Biosynthesis of Thiamine. VI. Incorporation of Formate into Carbon Atom Two of the Pyrimidine Moiety of Thiamine, n.d.; Brown, Gene M.; Kumaoka, Hiroshi (Box 51)
  - Methylated Bases of Ribosomal Ribonucleic Acid from HeLa Cells, n.d.; Brown, Gene M.; Yasuo Iwanami (Box 51)
  - Methylated Bases of Ribosomal Ribonucleic Acid from HeLa and L Cells, Brown, Gene M.; Yasuo Iwanami (Box 51)
  - Transfer Ribonucleic Acid Methylases of HeLa Cells, n.d.; Brown, Gene M.; Culp, Lloyd A. (Box 51)
  - Étude d'une Association du Virus et de son Hote la Drosophile: L'État Stabilisé, 1963; Brun, Gilbert (Box 52)
  - Coupled Mutations Involving Diverse Characters in Salmonella Blegdam, Jun. 1963; Bullas, Leonard R. (Box 52)
  - The Effect of Chloramphenicol on the Synthesis of DNA by E. Coli Infected with Phages T2 and T5, Jun. 1958; Burrous, S. and S. Paps (Box 52)
  - Contribution à l'Étude de l'Induction de l'Opéron Lactose d'Escherichia Coli, Jun. 1964; Burstein, Claude (Box 52)
  - Mécanismes Régulateurs dans la Biosynthèse des Enzymes du Métabolisme du Galactose Chez Escherichia Coli K12, Jun. 1963; Buttin, Gérard (Box 52)
    2 Folders
  - Synthèse Constitutive de Galactokinase Consécutive au Développement des Bactériophages L Chez Escherichia Coli K12, n.d.; Buttin, Gérard; Jacob, François, 1920-; Monod, Jacques (Box 52)
  - Recombination Experiments on Prophage Host Relationships, [1965]; Calef, Enrico; Marchelli, Carla (Box 52)
  - A Type of L Prophage Unable to Confer Immunity, n.d.; Calef, Enrico; Fischer Fantuzzi, Lia (Box 52)
  - Episomes in Evolution, n.d.; Campbell, Allan (Box 52)
  - An Unacknowledged Founding of Molecular Biology: H.J. Muller's Contributions to Gene Theory 1910-1936, [1970]; Carlson, Elof Axel (Box 52)
  - Biochemical Mutations in Bacteria, Jun. 1953; Carrington, George O., Jr. (Box 52)
  - Observations on the Genetics and Mating System of E. Coli K-12, Cavalli-Sforza, L.L.; Jinks, John L. (Box 53)
  - OCD's Five Year Plan: A Subsidy for the Department of Defense, n.d.; Cavers, David F. (Box 53)
  - Nucleotide Sequence and Gene Organization of ColE1 DNA, Chan, Peter T.; Lebowitz, Jacob; Ohmori, Horuo; Tomizawa, Jun-ichi (Box 53)
  - Sur les Propriétés Allostériques de la L-Thréonine-Désaminase d'Escherichia Coli K12, Jun. 1964; Changeux, Jean-Pierre (Box 53)
  - "False Correlations = Real Deaths: The Great Pellagra Cover-Up, 1914-1933", n.d.; Chase, Allan (Box 53)
  - Psychological Functions of Drug Use, Apr. 1968; Chein, Isidor (Box 53)
  - "Psychological, Social and Epidemiological Factors in Drug Addiction", Chein, Isidor (Box 53)
  - The Invasion of Panama, n.d.; [Chomsky, Noam?] (Box 53)
  - On Cognitive Structures and Their Development, Chomsky, Noam (Box 53)
  - The Abnormal Metabolic Response to Ultraviolet Light of a Recombination Deficient Mutant of Escherichia Coli K12, Boyce, Richard P.; Chamberlin, Michael; Clark, Alvin J.; Howard-Flanders, Paul (Box 53)
  - Inhibitor from Escherichia Coli Cells Blocks Initiation of Protein Synthesis, n.d.; Clark, Virginia L. (Box 53)
  - Isolation and Characterization of an Endogenous Inhibitor of Protein Synthesis in Escherichia Coli K12, Clark, Virginia L. (Box 53)
  - Colicin Factors and Episomes, 1962; Clowes, Royston C., 1921- (Box 53)
  - Serum Blocking Power of Lysate Supernatants of T2 and T4, 1954; Cohen, Seymour S., (Seymour Stanley), 1917-; Razzell, W.E. (Box 53)
  - Synchronization of Division of a Thymineless Mutant of Escherichia Coli, 1955; Barner, Hazel D.; Cohen, Seymour S., (Seymour Stanley), 1917- (Box 53)
  - "On the Behavior of the E. Coli Pz-Beta-Galactoside System Introduced into Shigella Dysenteriae""", n.d.; Cohn, Melvin; Lennox, E. S., (Edwin Samuel), 1920-; Spiegelman, Sol (Box 53)
  - Purification f Beta-Galactosidase from E. Coli, 10 Mar. 1958; Cohn, Melvin (Box 53)
  - Suppression and Complementation Among Mutants of the Regulatory Gene of the Lactose Operon of Escherichia Coli, Cohn, Melvin; Cohn-Bourgeois, Suzanne; Orgel, Leslie (Box 53)
  - Sur la Nature du Répresseur de l'Opéron Lactose d'Escherichia Coli, Nov. 1966; Cohn-Bourgeois, Suzanne (Box 53)
  - Scientists and the Misuse of Science, 1969; Collins, Frank (Box 53)
  - Viral Activation of Cell Response, Mar. 1960; Colter, J.S. and K.A.O. Ellem (Box 53)
  - [Position of Weakness Rather Than Strength], [1966]; Commager, Henry Steele (Box 53)
  - Homology Between Bacteriophage L DNA and E. Coli DNA, Cowie, Dean B.; McCarthy, Brian J. (Box 53)
  - DNA Gyrase and the Supercoiling of DNA, 1979; Cozzarelli, Nicholas R. (Box 53)